Guide to the Jacki Apple Papers 1984-2000 MSS 173
© 2010 Fales Library and Special Collections
The Jacki Apple Papers
1984-2000
MSS 173
© 2010 Fales Library and Special Collections
1.5 linear feet
Jacki Apple is a professor at Art Center College of Design in Pasadena, California. Her career has spanned through a range of the visual and media arts. Her radio show, Soundings, of which she was the host and producer, was on KPFK-FM Los Angeles Public Radio from 1981-1995. The Jacki Apple Papers includes correspondence with artists and listeners, promotional material from artists and record labels, memos and letters pertatining to KPFK Los Angeles Public Radio business, cue sheets, and recordings of music, audio art, and interviews that were featured on the show. The collection ranges from 1984-2000.
Apple, Jacki
Biographical Note
Jacki Apple is a visual, performance and media artist, writer, producer, and a professor at Art Center College of Design in Pasadena, California. Her career has spanned through a range of the visual and media arts. She has written, directed and produced interdisciplinary performance works, worked in costume design, composed and produced soundtracks, created multimedia installations, and worked with mediums of photography, audio, radio, film, site specific works, public art, and beyond.
Raised and educated in New York, Apple relocated to Los Angeles in 1981 where she continued to develop as an artist. An innovator in radio art, she was the host and producer of Soundings, her one hour weekly live radio show on KPFK-FM Los Angeles Public Radio from 1981-1995. Additionally, she co-produced the annual Earjam avant-garde music festival 2000-2004, and was a contributing editor to High Performance Magazine. She has written for numerous other art publications, and has taught at both the Art Center College of Design and the University of California, San Diego. In NYC she was a co-founder and first curator of Franklin Furnace 1976-1980. Apple's copious output of solo exhibitions, performance pieces, radio works, and installations have appeared all over the U.S. and throughout the world.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alpahbetically within each series.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Scope and Content
The Jacki Apple Papers includes correspondence with artists and listeners, promotional material from artists and record labels, memos and letters pertatining to KPFK Los Angeles Public Radio buisness, cue sheets, and recordings of music, audio art, and interviews that were featured on the show. The collection ranges from 1984-2000.
The collection is arranged by subject and by format. There are nine series:
Series I: KFPK Soundings
Series II: Record Label/Studios
Series III: Press/Promo/Catalogues
Series IV: Soundings- Radio Works/Spoken Word/Sound
Series V: Soundings- Music Tapes
Series VI: Radio Tapes with Jacki Apple/Audio Networks
Series VII: Radio Tapes with Jacki Apple/Soundings
Series VII: Artist Tapes
Series VIII: Soundings Miscellaneous
Provenance
The Jacki Apple Papers were donated by Jacki Apple to the NYU Libraries in 2005.
Anderson, Laurie, 1947-; Apple, Jacki; Burroughs, William S., 1914-1997; Gray, Spalding, 1941-2004; Russell, Arthur; Sondheim, Alan; Art |x Experimental methods.; Audiocassettes.; Audiotapes.; Avant-garde (Music); interviews; Los Angeles (Calif.); Personal correspondence.; Poetry |x Reading.; Press kits.; Press releases.; Promotional materials.; Sound recordings.
- Series I: KPFK Soundings
  - Artist Correspondence, 1987, 1989, 1990-1995, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Artist Letters and Distribution Letters, 1981-1983, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence/Business, 1979, 1986-1989, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - KPFK Cue Sheets 1 of 3, 1989-1995, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - KPFK Cue Sheets 2 of 3, 1985-1989, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - KPFK Cue Sheets 3 of 3, 1981-1984, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Listener Letters, 1986-1987, 1989, 1991-1994, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Promo Sheets/PR/Bios, 1986-1987, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II: Record Labels/Studios
  - Cuneiform Records (USA)/Rer Recommended (London), 1991, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Experimental Sound Studios/Lou Mallozi, 1987-1991, 1997, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lipp Service, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - No Problem, 1994-1997, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series III: Press/Promo/Catalogues (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Catalogues-Distribution CDs/Records/Tapes, 1990, 1992-1997, 1999, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1996, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Johnny Coleman, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Lynn Book Press Kit, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Misc- Press/Flyers/PR/Bios 1 of 2, 1987-1989, 1991-1992, 1993-1995, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Misc- Press/Flyers/PR/Bios 2 of 2, 1989, 1993-1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Press Kits, 1989, 1990, 1993, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Press Releases/Promotional Material, 1991-1996, 2000, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Press Releases/Promotional Material, 1992-1996, 1999, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Reviews, 1990, 1991, 1994, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Series IV: Audio: Soundings - Radio Works/Spoken Word/Sound, 1985-1995
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access Copies may not be available. Please consult a Fales archivist.
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - Mix Parade Vol.1 - Tom Skelly, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0001)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
      Format: 1/4" audiocassette
    - Mix Parade - Tom Skelly/Frank Ridenour, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0002)
    - Mix Parade #2 - Tom Skelly/Frank Ridenour, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0003)
    - This Is America - Terra Infirma, 1988 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0004)
    - The Campaign Game - E Productions [A]-- The Campaign Game [B]-- Situation Room (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0005)
    - RadioArcade - E Productions [A] Episode III- The American Dream [B]-- Episode IV - The Deep End, 1986 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0006)
    - War, Peace & Poetry: Guatemala - Weaving Rainbows From Black Sacks of Silence- Andrew Leslie Phillips, 1989 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0007)
    - Untitled #1 Essex Hemphill & Wayson Jones, Undated (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0008)
    - Untitled #2 Essex Hemphill & Wayson Jones, Undated (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0009)
    - Sound Pieces - Patsy Rahn, Undated (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0010)
    - Speak To Me - Paul Voudouris, Undated (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0011)
    - Untitled - Arleen Sclhoss, 1984 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0012)
    - Power of The Dreamer - Jimmy Townes/Trance Band, 1985 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0013)
    - It's All in the Wrist - Lisa Kucharski, 1995 (Box 2, Media 173.0014)
    - Kir Madiannand & Other Plays - Alison Lune, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0075)
    - A Change of Heart - Nicholas Smith, Undated (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0016)
    - Pressing the Flesh - The Manic Kingdom, 1992 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0017)
    - Sounds Familiar - Neville, Crotty & Sparling, Undated (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0018)
      Related Archival Materials note
- Series V: Audio: Soundings- Music Tapes, 1985-1995
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - Damaged - Alan Sondheim, 1986 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0019)
    - Damaged #2- [A]Square Dance the Rich [B] 1.Dallas Concert Live 2/3/86 2.Cricket 8/86 With Cricket - Alan Sondheim, 1986 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0020)
    - Rotated Guitar - Mark Wheaton, 1987 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0021)
    - de/signer- For String Quartet - David Dramm, 1988 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0022)
    - by - For Two Flutes - David Dramm, 1987 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0023)
    - Temple of Collage - Michael Avery Bell, 1989 (Box 2, Media 173.0024)
    - Being There - Michael Avery Bell, 1989 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0025)
    - Untitled- Non Credo, 1987 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0026)
    - Siren Song- Nigel Helyer, 1992 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0027)
    - Technical Tape - Science, 1986 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0028)
    - Breaded- Steaming Coils/Brad Laner, 1989 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0029)
    - Limpopo [Self-titled], 1991 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0030)
    - Omaggio a Futi - Motor Totemist Guild, 1988 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0031)
    - Untitled - Hisaso Shinagawa, 1992 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0032)
    - Untitled - Tom Guralnick/David Moss, 1988 (Box 2, Media ID: 173.0033)
    - Sonistruction - Tom Guralnick, 1988 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0034)
    - The Other Woman - Jill Fido, 1992 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0035)
    - Music From Performances - Yura Adams, Undated (Box 2, Media ID:173.0036)
    - Red Bird - Trevor Wishart, Undated (Box 2, Media ID:173.0037)
    - Suburban Bird Calls - D. Scott Hessels, Undated (Box 2, Media ID:173.0038)
    - CNLF Radio Sampler, Undated (Box 2, Media ID:173.0039)
    - Mindsight - Steve Nelson Rainey, Undated (Box 2, Media ID:173.0040)
    - The Blue Night/Lives of Saints - Fredrick Moore, Undated (Box 2, Media 173.0041)
    - While All Slept - YSC, 1993 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0042)
    - The Voices of Kwahn - Max Bilt, 1993 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0043)
    - Once Despised: Thine Eyes, Undated (Box 2, Media 173.0044)
    - Living Inside Design - Mikel Rouse, Undated (Box 2, Media ID:173.0045)
    - Smut - Dave Soldier, Undated (Box 2, Media ID:173.0046)
    - Talking Drum - Chris Brown, 1995 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0047)
    - Private Boundaries- Silent Tongues, 1992 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0048)
    - Let the Dead Bury the Living - Steve Gibson, 1993 (Box 2, Media ID:173.0049)
    - Feed Ink #1 - green - Audio Magazine from gamma Knife- Errant Bodies Productions, Undated (Box 2, Media ID:173.0050)
    - Feed Ink #2- silver- Audio Magazine from gamma KNife- Errant Bodies Productions, Undated (Box 2, Media ID:173.0051)
    - Feed Ink #3 - gold - Audio Magazine from Gamma Knife - Errant Bodies Productions (Box 2, Media ID:173.0052)
- Series VI: Audio: Radio Tapes with Jacki Apple/Audio Networks, 1982-1985
  Scope and Content
  Interviews & Live Performances with Jacki Apple
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - [A] Audio Networks Zone 23 - Rosenthal [B] Rosenthal Interview -- Rachel Rosenthal, 1982 (Box 3, Media ID:173.0053)
    - [A] Audio Networks:Zone 23 Burroughs/Anderson [B] Gierno/Kroser -- William Burroughs, Laurie Anderson, 1982 (Box 3, Media ID:173.0054)
    - [A] Jill Kroesen - Audio Networks: Zone 23 (1 of 2), 1982 (Box 3, Media ID:173.0055)
    - [A] Jill Kroesen - Audio Networks: Zone 23 (2 of 2), 1982 (Box 3, Media ID:173.0056)
    - [A] Jacki Apple, Robert Raposo, Bruce Tovsky Talk for One Hour, 1982 (Box 3, Media ID:173.0057)
    - [A] Audio Networks - Garrett List A-1 Band "Fire & Ice", 1982 (Box 3, Media 173.0058)
    - [A] Audio Networks Zone 23 - KPFK Los Angeles - Henry Korn, 1982 (Box 3, Media ID:173.0059)
    - [A] Gina Wendkos Interview, 1985 (Box 3, Media ID:173.0060)
    - [A] Harold Budd 10/14/85 - KFPK Auido Networks [B] New Music America Artists, 1985 (Box 3, Media ID:173.0061)
    - [A] Interview- Lee Breuer, Bob Telson, Jacki Apple, 1985 (Box 3, Media ID:173.0062)
    - Notes: On Performance - Tony Abatemarco, Jan Munroe, David Schweizer, Susan Falcon, 1985 (Box 3, Media ID:173.0063)
- Series VII: Audio: Radio Tapes with Jacki Apple/Soundings, 1986-1995
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - [A] Poets- Doug Messerli, 1986 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0064)
    - [A] Bob & Bob Retro, 1986 (Box 3, Media 173.0065)
    - [A] KFPK 6/30/87 - Dark Bob, 1987 (Box 3, Media ID: 173. 0066)
    - [A] John Malpede - LAPD - Aug 86, 1986 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0067)
    - [A] Rachel Rosenthal- Interview- Sept 1, 1987 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0068)
    - [A] Barry Yourgraw - Dec 8 1987 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0069)
    - [A] Remy Charlip/Steve Arnold/Car/Stone/Kedric Wolfe etc - 2/16/88, 1988 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0070)
    - [A] Irie! March 19, 1988 - British Dance Co. (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0071)
    - [A] Elisha Shapiro - Nihilist Party Political Convention, 1988 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0072)
    - [A] LAPD (Los Angeles Poverty Dept Theater) - Frank, George, John, Undated [1980's] (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0073)
    - [A] Belief - 8/7/90 - Elisha Shapiro, 1990 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0074)
    - [A] Elisha Shapiro/Beth Lapides Live, 1992 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0075)
    - [A] Terry Sweeney/Nancy Regan Performance, Undated [1990's] (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0076)
    - [A] Spalding Gray Live- 4/19/94 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0077)
    - [A] Larry Miller & William de Ridder Live- Fluxus - 8/23/94, 1994 (Box 3, Media ID: 173. 0078)
    - [A] Women Vocalists (recorded) - 5/26/95, 1995 (Box 3, Media ID: 173. 0079)
- Series VII: Audio: Artists Tapes, 1990-1996
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - [A] Anna Holmer & Geert Waegman - Blue Flame Blue, Undated (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0080)
    - Untitled - Anna Holmer/Rod Poole, 1993 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0081)
    - [A] Tim Rowe- Six Broken Lines - Rowe, Miano, Onserud, Miles, Kono, Siwula, 1996 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0082)
    - [A] Audio Portraits - Tom Skelly, Undated (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0083)
    - [A] Port Menteau: Overlooking the Insignia [B] X's Malingering/Forefinger Ajar - Sue Fishbein, Undated (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0084)
    - [A] Quiver - Dean Terry, 1994 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0085)
    - [A] Curled Wire - Tim Boroian, 1990 (Box 3, Media ID: 173.0086)
- Series VIII: Audio: Soundings Miscellaneous
  - Beat Town - Peter Beckman, Undated (Box 4, Media ID: 173.0087)
    1/4" Audio Reel Speed: 15 IPS Stereo
    General note
    Live Mix-Master